export const chapter = "Chapter - 7: Pronouns";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "What is the purpose of using pronouns in sentences or speech?",
          optionA: "To emphasize nouns",
          optionB: "To enhance vocabulary",
          optionC: "To avoid repetition of nouns",
          correctAnswer: "To avoid repetition of nouns",
        },
        {
          question: "Which of the following is NOT a pronoun?",
          optionA: "Horse",
          optionB: "They",
          optionC: "It",
          correctAnswer: "Horse",
        },
        {
          question:
            "In the sentence, 'Riya is a young girl. She has a ball,' what does 'she' refer to?",
          optionA: "The ball",
          optionB: "Riya",
          optionC: "The playground",
          correctAnswer: "Riya",
        },
        {
          question: "What are pronouns described as in the text?",
          optionA: "Enemies of nouns",
          optionB: "Substitutes for nouns",
          optionC: "Synonyms of nouns",
          correctAnswer: "Substitutes for nouns",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How do pronouns contribute to sentences according to the text?",
          optionA: "They make sentences longer",
          optionB: "They make sentences shorter and clearer",
          optionC: "They complicate sentences",
          correctAnswer: "They make sentences shorter and clearer",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which word in the sentence 'It eats green grass and fodder' is a pronoun?",
          optionA: "Eats",
          optionB: "Green",
          optionC: "It",
          correctAnswer: "It",
        },
        {
          question: "What do pronouns act as, according to the text?",
          optionA: "Opponents of nouns",
          optionB: "Friends of nouns",
          optionC: "Replacements for nouns",
          correctAnswer: "Replacements for nouns",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What effect does the use of pronouns have on sentences, as described in the text?",
          optionA: "They make sentences sound informal",
          optionB: "They make sentences sound repetitive",
          optionC: "They make sentences concise and pleasant",
          correctAnswer: "They make sentences concise and pleasant",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which of the following sentences demonstrates the use of pronouns effectively?",
          optionA: "'The horse has a large body. The horse can run very fast.'",
          optionB:
            "'The horse has a large body. It eats green grass and fodder.'",
          optionC: "'The horse has a large body. It can run very fast.'",
          correctAnswer: "'The horse has a large body. It can run very fast.'",
        },
        {
          question: "What do pronouns represent in sentences?",
          optionA: "Abstract concepts",
          optionB: "Concrete nouns",
          optionC: "Specific adjectives",
          correctAnswer: "Concrete nouns",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Riya is a young girl. ___ has a ball. Riya goes to the playground in the evening.",
          optionA: "He",
          optionB: "She",
          optionC: "They",
          correctAnswer: "She",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The horse is a domestic animal. ___ has a large body. It eats green grass and fodder.",
          optionA: "He",
          optionB: "She",
          optionC: "It",
          correctAnswer: "It",
        },
        {
          question: "Pronouns are used to avoid ___ of nouns.",
          optionA: "repetition",
          optionB: "understanding",
          optionC: "substitution",
          correctAnswer: "repetition",
        },
        {
          question: "___ are friends of Nouns.",
          optionA: "Adjectives",
          optionB: "Pronouns",
          optionC: "Verbs",
          correctAnswer: "Pronouns",
        },
        {
          question:
            "In the sentence, 'The horse has a large body. ___ can run very fast.'",
          optionA: "It",
          optionB: "They",
          optionC: "He",
          correctAnswer: "It",
        },
        {
          question: "___ is a word that is used in place of a Noun.",
          optionA: "Verb",
          optionB: "Pronoun",
          optionC: "Adverb",
          correctAnswer: "Pronoun",
        },
        {
          question: "The parents and teachers admire ___.",
          optionA: "Him",
          optionB: "Her",
          optionC: "Them",
          correctAnswer: "Him",
        },
        {
          question: "Riya plays with ___ friend.",
          optionA: "She",
          optionB: "Her",
          optionC: "Their",
          correctAnswer: "Her",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The words which we have used for Riya and the horse are known as ___.",
          optionA: "Substitutes",
          optionB: "Antonyms",
          optionC: "Pronouns",
          correctAnswer: "Pronouns",
        },
        {
          question: "The horse can run very fast because ___ has a large body.",
          optionA: "She",
          optionB: "He",
          optionC: "It",
          correctAnswer: "It",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question: "Pronouns are used to avoid repetition of nouns.",
          optionA: "Correct",
          optionB: "Incorrect",
          correctAnswer: "Correct",
        },
        {
          question: "A pronoun is a word used in place of a verb.",
          optionA: "Correct",
          optionB: "Incorrect",
          correctAnswer: "Incorrect",
        },
        {
          question: "Pronouns make sentences longer and complicated.",
          optionA: "Correct",
          optionB: "Incorrect",
          correctAnswer: "Incorrect",
        },
        {
          question: "The purpose of pronouns is to emphasize nouns.",
          optionA: "Correct",
          optionB: "Incorrect",
          correctAnswer: "Incorrect",
        },
        {
          question: "Pronouns act as substitutes for nouns.",
          optionA: "Correct",
          optionB: "Incorrect",
          correctAnswer: "Correct",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Using pronouns in sentences often makes them concise and pleasant.",
          optionA: "Correct",
          optionB: "Incorrect",
          correctAnswer: "Correct",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The words 'I,' 'you,' 'he,' 'she,' and 'it' are examples of pronouns.",
          optionA: "Correct",
          optionB: "Incorrect",
          correctAnswer: "Correct",
        },
        {
          question: "Pronouns are enemies of nouns.",
          optionA: "Correct",
          optionB: "Incorrect",
          correctAnswer: "Incorrect",
        },
        {
          question: "Pronouns represent abstract concepts in sentences.",
          optionA: "Correct",
          optionB: "Incorrect",
          correctAnswer: "Incorrect",
        },
        {
          question: "Pronouns can't replace nouns in sentences.",
          optionA: "Correct",
          optionB: "Incorrect",
          correctAnswer: "Incorrect",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
